Thank You, Lord!
I hope you are thanking Jesus in your hearts.
Nowadays, we have substitutes -
belief for action - which is wrong.
When we see people saying, "I believe in healing.
I believe in salvation. I believe in this, that..." -
It is not enough to believe in healing.
It is not enough to just believe in healing,
or whatever you are seeking.
It is something we must reach out, in faith.
That is why many times we get disappointed.
"I believe, I believe..."
Many of you are here because you believe
but you must reach out in faith.
That is, we must speak our faith and act our faith.
Not just speak, "Yes..."
It must be from your heart.
If you want to demonstrate that 'Yes',
it must also be from your heart.
I should not just come out because I believe;
I must come out because I have faith.
If you say you believe, Jesus will work for you
– belief in our heart is released by faith -
how will that belief be released?
The belief in our heart can only be
released by faith out of our mouth.
“I believe Jesus will work for me.”
Where is your faith?
Faith is practical.
If you believe, where is your faith?
If you believe Jesus will heal you,
you should also reach out in faith;
you must have the work of faith in that matter.
"I'm having a headache. I believe Jesus will heal me."
If I really believe Jesus will heal me,
I must reach out in faith to Jesus.
How do we reach out in faith?
With that headache I should
not be distressed, or worried.
I should not be worried.
People should greet me;
I should be able to say, "How are you?"
"Fine."
I should not look sad; that means
I've reached out in faith.
Today, we say, "I believe Jesus will heal me",
but you are still worried, distressed, in anxiety,
and you say you believe Jesus will heal you.
Where is your work of faith?
That means your faith is fake.
You are expecting money from someone;
you don't have money -
somebody promised you and you
believe in God that the man will pay.
At that moment you should begin to be happy, even begin to look for what you want to buy with this money,
even reach out to the market saying,
"How much is this? 10 dollars, 20 dollars..."
You have not received that money, but you tell them,
"I'm coming back. Will you be here? tomorrow?
I will be here tomorrow. I'm coming back."
It means you have reached out in faith.
It is not the situation, where you say, you
believe that the man will pay you the money
but you are still at home, worrying, thinking,
"What if the man will not pay me? What will I do?"
You are worried as if you have never prayed at all.
I hope you know the work of faith now.
It is not enough to believe.
Today, we have substituted belief for action.
We should not substitute belief for action.
‘Action’ is still there because belief is released by faith.
You must speak your faith and act
your faith to activate God’s power.
You cannot activate God’s power without
speaking words of faith and acting faith.
'Fake people' can say, "I believe".
If you are not genuine, you can hide under 'belief'.
You say, "I believe Jesus. I'm a believer." - fake people.
Those who are not genuine,
"I'm a believer. I'm born-again."
If you believe, you should have the
work of faith in that matter.
"I believe. Jesus will heal me." - your faith should change immediately, if you have work of faith.
Smile!
Greet people around you as if you don't have pain.
Give a phone call to people, "How are you?"
Don't look sad, greet.
If someone around you needs help,
give out: "What do you need?"
That's belief; the job is done.
Healing is something, deliverance is
something, salvation is something;
we must reach out in faith.
Speak your faith and act your
faith to activate God’s power.
Like you are sitting now; if you are really here and you believe God - God will work for you today -
you begin to be happy.
When that healing has not happened, begin to be happy.
Show your joy.
Smile.
Help people, as if you are giving testimony;
that is work of faith.
Faith is expecting Jesus to do what He promised to do.
Remember father Abraham.
God is not a man that lies.
He said He will do it and He will do it.
If the Son says He will do it, He will do it.
But if your friend says he will do it, he may not do it.
If your father says he will do it, he may not do it.
If your mummy says she will do it, she may not do it but if the Son says He will do it, He will do it indeed!
That is the work of faith.
Faith is practical.
You must always show your faith when you believe.
It goes together: faith – belief,
just like prayer and Bible reading;
one is not complete without the other.
Belief and faith should always go together;
Tell your neighbour.
Prayer and Bible reading should always go together;
one is not complete without the other.
In the same vein, belief and faith should always go together; one is not complete without the other.
If you say you believe, you must have the work of faith.
Tell your neighbour.
I cannot hear you.
If you say you believe, you must have the work of faith.
Faith releases belief in our heart
just as a key opens the locked door.
Put the key - it will open.
Faith releases belief in our heart.
No faith – your belief would be dormant in your heart.
That is why when you speak,
you speak the word of faith;
act faith to activate God’s power.
There are two things you noticed today.
One: prayer and Bible reading
should always go together,
but you on your own - you always pray,
without reading Bible.
Where do you get the Word?
The Word you use in prayer is the
Word of God, not your word.
The Word you use, "Father, help me..."
There are two "help" - the language of your own help, and the language of the Bible.
"Come!" - there are two "come".
Man has the ability to come;
the Holy Spirit comes as He wills.
It means man has the word, ‘Come’; the
Holy Spirit also has His own Word, ‘Come’.
"Good Morning" - there are two "Good Morning".
Man has the ability to say, “Good Morning”; the Holy Spirit of God also says, “Good Morning”.
Which one are you using, when you are
not reading your Bible before praying?
There are two "walk" - see me.
Man has the ability to walk, Holy Spirit walks.
Who is walking here now?
Look at me - who is walking?
You don't know - that is the problem.
Because you look with man's eyes,
not the eyes of the Holy Spirit.
So, you don't know who is walking here.
That's why you can blaspheme,
speak against, do anything.
An evil thought in your heart, "Look at him,
see the way he walks..."
You don't even know who is walking.
See - who is walking here?
You don't know.
Because you can only know who is walking,
when you look with the eyes of faith.
That is, when the Holy Spirit looks through
you, you know who is walking.
If you look, you see a man, but if your look
is a look of the Holy Spirit, you see God's being.
That's the problem.
When it comes to the things of the
Spirit in this world, there is a problem.
If God comes today, He will only show
mercy of taking you to the Kingdom;
by His mercy you will go to His Kingdom.
You cannot see Him, talk to Him, relate
with Him - how will you live for Him?
If today is our last day on earth, those of us
that will go, will go by His highly mercy.
Not because you live for Him.
How will you live for Someone you don't relate with?
How can you live for Someone you
cannot even interact with?
You don't know when He is talking,
how He is talking...
You cannot tell me how you relate with your God.
That is a big problem, when it
comes to things of the Spirit.
It is very disappointing; after you have
finished your Bible, three times, four times,
from Genesis to Revelation, you can preach
any verses, even you can write the Bible,
yet - you don't know God.
Very disappointing.
When we are talking of knowing God, there are simple
ways to start from, instead of deceiving ourselves.
"Yes, I have the Word, I've studied the Word..."
This Word of God, the Bible is the
letter inspired by the Holy Spirit.
If it is a letter inspired by the Holy Spirit of God, it means the thought of it is from the Spirit of God.
Now, it is the Spirit of God that we should know.
How do we know Him?
By having a free spirit.
A free spirit is a spirit that is not locked up by sin.
What are those things?
Holding grudges, envy, jealousy, pain of the past.
These are sins.
"Somebody has cheated me, embarrassed me" - grieve, grudges, envy, strive, unforgiving spirit - these are sins.
You cannot have a free spirit when
you are locked up by sin.
These are the fruits of the sin.
Tell your neighbour.
A free spirit is a spirit that is not locked up by sin.
What are the sins?
Envy, jealousy, pain of the past, unforgiving
spirit, just name them – these are sins.
When those things lock up your spirit,
your spirit can never be free.
A free spirit is sensitive to the Spirit
of God and if a spirit is locked up by sin,
it cannot be sensitive to the Spirit of God.
You want to go for God, you love God - it is not possible,
because you are locked, you are in the prison.
The human spirit, when free, is sensitive
to the Spirit of God.
Tell your neighbour.
The human spirit, when free,
is sensitive to the Spirit of God.
If it is bound or burdened, it loses that sensitivity.
When it loses that sensitivity, what else again?
Therefore, it is useless as an instrument.
Many of our spirits are useless.
The purpose of your spirit is to attract that Spirit of God
but it’s useless because it’s locked up
by envy, jealousy, anger, pain of the past.
The purpose of your spirit is to attract God,
work with God, marry God and admire God.
"This is God!" - Everywhere, anything of God because He is your Creator!
You want to admire Him, you want to marry Him, you want to walk with Him,
but it is useless now because of envy, jealousy - you can think of all those things that locked up your spirit.
Let someone say, "Free spirit".
The human spirit, when free,
is sensitive to the Spirit of God.
That is, your spirit when free is sensitive,
it attracts, it marries, it loves God.
If you say you love God, when your
spirit is locked, you are deceiving yourself.
I can see now the reason why we are trying to love God, we try to follow God, we say we love God.
When there is prayer, you see people
crying, "Oh, my God..."
He is trying to love God.
No way.
It is better to know your problem than not.
"This is my problem - OK"; you continue to battle with it.
"This is my problem. I don't know; I thought I knew the Bible."
"Oh! This is my problem. My spirit is locked up."
Tell your neighbour.
This is my problem.
My spirit is locked up.
This is my story this is my song
Praising my Saviour all the day long
You don't have a problem.
The only problem you have is
that your spirit is locked up.
"My spirit is locked up."
Tell your neighbour.
If you agree with me, let me see your hand.
Please, if you agree with me,
raise up your hand that you agree.
All this, Genesis, this, that - stop that.
Your spirit is locked up.
How to open it?
How to be free and become an instrument?
That is what we have to talk about now.
Your spirit is locked up.
Envy, jealousy, anger, all this, is an instrument that locks my spirit.
If my spirit is not free, it can never be sensitive to the Spirit of God; it will lose that sensitivity.
This is nail and magnet; if you bring them...
But when your spirit is locked up, it can't magnetize.
Thank You, Lord.
In Jesus Christ's name.
You can see the reason why I don't reply critics.
They say this, that; I will remain silent, because I don't want anything to lock up my spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You will never hear me standing here and
criticizing ministers of God, or any church,
that they are this, that -
I don't want anything to lock up my spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I will not stand on Emmanuel TV and say, "Hey, miracle - come to The Synagogue and worship".
No.
Does it mean other churches are not good?
I don't want anything to lock up my spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you are coming from the airport, you are supposed to see Synagogue sign boards everywhere.
No, we don't have any sign boards, no sign posts.
This is not the only living church;
there are other living churches.
I don't want anything to lock up my spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When I wake up in the morning and I'm coming to the service, they will put all the dresses, suits, fine ones.
I say, "No no no. Just give me a simple one.
Remember, they are here to see Prophet T.B. Joshua, not Mr T.B. Joshua".
If you pay much attention on Mr T.B. Joshua,
it becomes a sin.
It is Mr T.B. Joshua that puts on the dress.
If Mr T.B. Joshua dresses
gorgeously and says, "Hello, hi..."
and you are sitting down and begin to count,
"How much are those shoes?
How much is this dress? Look at him! Oh my God!"
It becomes a sin and it will lock up my spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Criticizing, abusing, jealousy, envy...
You hear something you don't want to hear...
It is what you want hear, you will hear.
If people know that you are on the side of God - what is pure, clean, admirable,
is all what you want to hear - those things will be coming to you.
But if it is what is condemning, destroying, criticizing, killing, destroying, stealing is what you want to hear,
those things will be coming to you, to destroy
your spirit and to lock up your spirit.
I have been praying for you to know better.
When you are rebuking me, banning me,
praying against me, I keep praying for you,
because I don't want anything to lock up my spirit.
Because my spirit is an instrument to
attract God's Spirit, to walk with God's Spirit.
If the spirit were locked, you would not be
able to come here today.
All what we are seeing happening in
the life of T.B. Joshua would not happen.
It is because my spirit is sensitive,
attracting God's Spirit,
that is why you see miracle, deliverance,
all this happen.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You don’t need to be perfect to be used
by God but you need to be available.
You are available, when you do away with
those things and allow your spirit to be free.
Something may have happened to you
yesterday - put it behind you.
I’m married to Jesus
Satan leave me alone
My husband is coming to take me away
To everlasting home
What is the meaning of that?
I'm married to what?
Jesus.
I’m married to love
Hatred leave me alone
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I’m married to faithfulness
Unfaithfulness leave me alone
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is the meaning.
Their nature is what the Bible is talking
about; the nature of satan - leave me,
the nature of God - I'm married with You.
I'm married to goodness; bad - leave me alone.
I'm married to faithfulness; unfaithfulness,
leave me alone.
I'm married to humility; pride - leave me alone.
I'm married to love, hatred - leave me alone.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is it.
But in your own case, you think marrying to Jesus...
- where will you see Jesus to marry?
You can only get married to His nature.
Tell your neighbour.
Where will you see Him?
You can only get married to His nature.
I cannot hear you; stand up!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Where will you see Him to do wedding?
You can only wed who?
His nature, faithfulness, kindness,
goodness, humility, love!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You can only marry His nature.
He is talking about His nature.
His nature - when you know that,
you know how to live your life.
Leave me unfaithfulness, I'm married with faithfulness.
Leave me disobedience, I'm married with obedience.
That is what we are talking about.
Viewers, thank you.
TT ROBERT BEGIER 24/07/2018
RV Lizz ndung'u 03/09/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 16/09/2018